Austin Davis

Data Analyst

- (615) 948-6301
- addavis191@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/ austin-davis123/
- github.com/ austin-davis

SKILLS

Excel, SQL, PowerBI, Tableau, Python, GitHub

Public Speaking

Training Program Development

Analytical & Critical Thinking

Planning & Coordination

New Hire Training

Synchronous & Asynchronous Teaching

EDUCATION

August 2022

Nashville Software School

Data Analytics Certification

August 2017

Tennessee Language Center

TEFL Certification
Teaching English as a
Foreign Language

May 2014

Miami University (OH)

Bachelor of Arts
History & Russian Studies

ABOUT

Articulate instructor with a passion for using education & data to create successful employees. With a diverse range of experiences, highly effective at supporting multiple projects concurrently while maintaining focus to deliver results. Analytical & organized leader comfortable working remotely & in person, both independently & as part of a team.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

May 2022 - Present

Data Analytics Student - Nashville Software School

- Intensive introduction to data analytics & business intelligence tools
 - o Excel, PostgreSQL, Github, Power BI, Tableau, Python
- Emphasis on building technical skills through project-based learning
- Lahman Baseball Project PostgreSQL
 - Utilized JOINS, UNIONS, Common Table Expressions (CTE's), Sub Queries, & CASE statements to analyze 27 tables
- Built and deployed dashboards using Tableau and PowerBl
- UN GDP and Internet Use Project Python
 - Used pandas, seaborn, & jupyter notebook

January 2021 - Present

English as a Second Language Instructor - Tennessee Language Center

- Designed and taught a 120 hour curriculum for intermediate and advanced business English learners.
- Developed an online matrix learning management system for asynchronous and synchronous learning.

January 2021 – June 2022

Independent Contractor - Guardian HealthCare

- Created & maintained a data management solution to streamline reporting from 300+ program participants.
- Provided data driven solutions for program development & distribution to multinational clients.

October 2018 - May 2020

Education & Training Manager - Nashville CBD Solutions

- Built a training program, conducted orientation sessions, & organized continuing education opportunities for all team members.
- Developed print based marketing materials & consumer education pamphlets.
- Launched an educational program in the local community & organized outreach events & to grow the regional store presence.

August 2017 - December 2019

English as a Second Language Instructor - Tennessee Language Center

- Certified to teach adults, adolescents, & young learners of English in both group & private classes.
- Employed the PPP (presentation, practice, production) method during lessons to teach adult learners conversational English.
- Focused on business English proficiency for professional learners.
- Worked with youth & adult refugees for preliterate language acquisition.